Rohan Dhiman

LinkedIn: rohan-dhiman-923a21144

Address: Apt 1208, 1280 Rue Saint Marc, Montreal, QC H3H2G1 Email: rohansarnjitdhiman@gmail.com | Mobile: 438-927-9468

SUMMARY

Current Masters of Applied Computer Science student at Concordia University, Montreal. I have an experience of 1.5 years in FrontEnd & API development at India's largest IT Company TCS for the client State Bank Of India. I'm very interested in learning about and working with emerging digital technologies. Interested in developing a better problem-solving method for difficult tasks, as well as learning new technologies and tools as needed.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & COURSE WORK

: Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VB.Net, Python Languages

Frameworks : React.js, Apache Hadoop, Node.js

Databases : MySQL, PostgreSQL

Dev Tools : Visual Studio, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Jupyter NoteBook, Git, Amazon AWS EC2, UiPath, Google DialogFlow,

Google Firebase, Salesforce

Testing : Unit Testing (JUnit), White Box Testing, Grey Box Testing, Black Box Testing

: Windows, Linux, MacOS

: Agile, Waterfall, Iterative methods Methodologies

Course Work : Programming And Problem Solving, Advance Programming Practices, Distributed System Design, Big-

> Data Analytics, Software Design Methodologies, Data Structures and Algorithm, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management Systems, Web Technology, Computer Networks, Cloud Computing,

Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning

EXPERIENCE

Assistant System Engineer - Front-End Developer

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd

Oct 2020 - Mar 2022 Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Worked on the client side for State Bank Of India one of India's Largest Bank
- My role was to develop the Banks Front-End application that was used by the Branch Teller's.
- The application is being used in all the 28,000 branches across India.
- The coding languages that I have worked on were VB.NET, Java, HTML, JavaScript & XML

Research Analyst Intern

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

Organic Bots , Incubator Center

Remote - North Carolina, USA

- Worked with Robotic Process Automation, Machine Learning and Blockchain Technologies
- Worked on researching and building small applications using UiPath, Google DialogFlow and Machine Learning classifiers.
- Applications that I built included a ChatBot using Google DialogFlow, UiPath Application for text scrapping automation for application form filling and Fake News Detection using Naive Bayes Algorithm.

Intern

1 June 2019 - 30 June 2019 Pune, Maharashtra, India

Sandvik Asia Pvt. Ltd

Worked for the Industrial Project titled 'IT Asset Management System'.

- My role here was to develop in-house projects for the company which were used for the employees as well as to handle the working of the production machines used in the company.
- Coding languages that I got to work on was C Sharp (MVC Architecture).

EDUCATION

Concordia University

Masters of Applied Computer Science

Pune University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Montreal, Quebec, Canada. Sept 2022 - Apr 2024

Pune, Maharashtra, India Aug 2016 - Apr 2020

Water Treatment Plant Data Analysis

Clustering, Plotting, Classification, Machine Learning

- Demonstrated experience in utilizing machine learning methods to optimize operations at a Water Treatment Plant (WTP).
- Utilized statistical methods such as Pearson correlation coefficient and Spearman rank correlation coefficient to find the correlation between different attributes.
- Visualized correlations using scatter plots and clustered water samples based on their similar characteristics using K-Means and Hierarchical Clustering methods.
- Implemented classification methods like decision trees, random forests, neural networks, and support vector machines (SVM) to predict which water samples are healthy or hazardous.

<u>Distributed Movie Ticket Booking System</u> Java, Java RMI, User Datagram Protocol(UDP), Distributed System Design

- Designed and developed a Distributed Java application for booking of Movie tickets on three different theatre servers Java, Java RMI and User Datagram Protocol(UDP)
- There were three different servers created assumed for three theatres. The client and server connection was implemented using Java RMI.
- Server to Server connectivity was established using UDP.
- The Admin user could create movie slots, remove movie slots and view the movie slots available on all servers. The customer user could book a movie ticket, cancel a movie ticket and also view the movie tickets he/she booked accross all servers.

Flight Ticket Booking Software

Java, PostgreSQL, API

• Built a user friendly software to book tickets. The flight data was downloaded using the Skyscanner API and database operations were performed using **PostgreSQL**.

Covid 19 Fact Checker

Multinomial Naive Bayes, AWS EC2, Python

Developed a user-friendly web-based application to detect whether a news related to Covid is fake or real. The
application was developed using machine learning training model Multinomial Naïve Bayes and was deployed on
the web using Amazon Web Services EC2.

Built A ChatBot For College Library Website

Google DialogFlow, Google Firebase

- Developed a chatbot for my college library.
- The chatbot was used to handle library-related questions from college students.

PUBLICATIONS

Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes

 Pradhan M.A., Shinde A., Dhiman R., Ghorpade S., Jawale S. (2021) Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes. In: Satapathy S.C., Bhateja V., Favorskaya M.N., Adilakshmi T. (eds) Smart Computing Techniques and Applications. Smart Innovation, Systems and Technologies, vol 224. Springer, Singapore. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-16-1502-3_81

ACHIEVEMENTS & PARTICIATION

Code19 Hackathon Team Leader

 Won the Third Prize with a grant of \$3000 in the Motwani Jadeja Foundation Code 19 Hackathon for my final year project "Covid 19 Fact Checker".

Research Paper Presentation

Presenter

 Presented our research paper titled "Fact Check Using Multinomial Naive Bayes" in the 4th INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SMART COMPUTING AND INFORMATICS (SCI-2020), Hyderabad, India.

Engineering Today AISSMS COE

Technical Head

• Was chosen to be the Head for the college's Tech Fest titled Engineering Today 2019-20.

Internet Of Things - By BiEmbedly

Work Shop

• Participated in a 2 day workshop where we were given hands-on training on Internet Of Things.

Core Java Training - By Internshala Trainings

Training

• Attended a six week online winter training on Core Java.